<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<seiscomp>
	<plugin name="chain">
		<extends>seedlink</extends>
		<description>Global options for the chain plugin</description>
		<configuration>
			<group name="plugins">
				<group name="chain">
					<parameter name="dialupConnections" type="int" default="0">
						<description>
							Defines the maximum number of concurrent dial-up
							connections. A value of 0 does not limit the
							concurrent connections.
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="loadTimeTable" type="boolean" default="true">
						<description>
							If enabled load_timetable is used by the chain plugin to request
							the available time windows of each stream in the Seedlink buffer
							to discard older records.
						</description>
					</parameter>
				</group>
			</group>
		</configuration>
	</plugin>
	<binding module="seedlink" name="chain" category="sources">
		<description>Seedlink server (TCP/IP)</description>
		<configuration>
			<parameter name="address" type="string" default="geofon.gfz-potsdam.de">
				<description>
					Hostname or IP of the Seedlink server.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="port" type="int" default="18000">
				<description>Port of the Seedlink server</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="selectors" type="list:string">
				<description>
					List of stream selectors. If left empty all available
					streams will be requested. See slinktool manpage for
					more information.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="proc" type="string">
				<description>
				Name of the proc object (defined in streams.xml); used for processing
				raw streams (streams submitted by a plugin as raw samples).
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="station" type="string">
				<description>
					Defines the input station if different from the stations
					code. Usually leave this parameter unconfigured. If
					configured and different from the stations code
					the station code will be renamed to match the local station
					code.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="network" type="string">
				<description>
					Defines the input network if different from the stations
					network. Usually leave this parameter unconfigured. If
					configured and different from the stations network code
					the network code will be renamed to match the local network
					code.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="group" type="string">
				<description>
					Usually stations with the same source addresses and dialup
					options are grouped together and managed by a chain plugin
					process. You can give here an additional group ID. Available
					placeholders are $NET and $STA that are replaced by the
					network code or station code. Whitespaces are replaced by
					underscores when generating chain.xml.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="defaultTimingQuality" type="int">
				<description>
					The default timing quality is used when unpacking data that
					does not contain blockette 1001, that allows SeedLink to
					construct blockette 1001 for downsampled data.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="overlapRemoval" type="string">
				<description>
					If overlap removal is set to "initial" or "full", then
					earlier records will be discarded (record number is used
					in case several subsequent records have the same header time).
					All other values are treated as "none". Leave this option
					unset unless you know what you are doing.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="batchmode" type="boolean" default="true">
                                <description>
					If enabled then the chain plugin tries to subscribe for
					channels with the BATCH command which is magnitudes faster
					than the old handshake. Not all SeedLink servers support
					the BATCH mode so it needs to be turned off in case of
					problems. 
				</description>
                        </parameter>
			<group name="dialup">
				<parameter name="enable" type="boolean" default="false">
					<description>
						Enables dialup mode. Needs schedule and uptime to be
						set accordingly.
					</description>
				</parameter>
				<parameter name="uptime" type="int" default="600">
					<description>
						Dialup uptime in seconds.
					</description>
				</parameter>
				<parameter name="schedule" type="string" default="0,30 * * * *">
					<description>
						The dialup schedula in cron format.
					</description>
				</parameter>
				<parameter name="ifup" type="string">
					<description>An optional dialup ifup script.</description>
				</parameter>
				<parameter name="ifdown" type="string">
					<description>An optional dialup ifdown script.</description>
				</parameter>
			</group>
			<group name="channels">
				<parameter name="rename" type="list:string">
					<description>
						Allows to rename channels. This is a list of
						strings where each item defines one mapping in the
						format "SRC_LOCCHA:DST_LOCCHA". Either SRC_LOCCHA or
						DST_LOCCHA may contain wildcard characters (question
						mark) and the location code (LOC) in both identifiers
						is optional.
					</description>
				</parameter>
				<parameter name="unpack" type="list:string">
					<description>
						Allows to unpack channels instead of sending them as
						miniseed to Seedlink. Unpacked streams can be downsampled
						by Seedlink. This is a list of strings where each item
						defines one unpack mapping  in the format
						"SRC_LOCCHA:DST_ID:1" where DST_ID can
						be an arbitrary channel id which must match the definition of
						a stream in streams.xml. The last ":1" is optional and defines
						if the unpacked data should be doubled (duplicate each sample).
						In case rename mappings are active, SRC_LOCCHA referes to
						the final channel name after renaming.
					</description>
				</parameter>
			</group>
		</configuration>
	</binding>
</seiscomp>
