<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<seiscomp>
	<module name="scmaster" category="Messaging">
		<configuration>
			<parameter name="msgGroups" type="list:string">
				<description>
				Configures the available message groups. If nothing is configured, the default message
				groups AMPLITUDE, PICK, LOCATION, MAGNITUDE, FOCMECH, EVENT, QC, PUBLICATION, GUI, INVENTORY,
				CONFIG, LOGGING, SERVICE_REQUEST and SERVICE_PROVIDE are provided.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="schemaVersionOverride" type="string">
				<description>
				Force the schema version to be reported to clients. This must be equal
				or lower than the one the code supports otherwise scmaster will fail to
				start. This is an expert setting and can be required if clients with
				version equal or lower than 2013.245 connect to a master with a higher
				schema version because of a bug on client side.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<group name="admin">
				<parameter name="adminname" type="string">
					<description>
					Name of admin user used to authenticate with scadmin to manage
					client connections.
					</description>
				</parameter>
				<parameter name="password" type="string">
					<description>
					Password of admin user used to authenticate with scadmin to manage
					client connections.
					</description>
				</parameter>
			</group>
			<group name="plugins">
				<group name="dbPlugin">
					<description>
					Database plugin for scmaster. This plugin forwards all messages received by
					scmaster to the configured database and garantuees that the objects in the
					message (send within notifiers) are stored in the database before a client
					receives the message. To load the plugin, add dbplugin to plugins in scmaster's
					configuration.
					</description>
					<parameter name="dbDriver" type="string">
						<description>
						Selected the database driver to use. Database drivers are
						available through plugins. The default plugin is dbmysql
						which supports the MYSQL database server. It is activated
						with the core.plugins parameter.
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="readConnection" type="string">
						<description>
						Sets the database read connection which is reported to clients
						that connect to this server. If a remote setup should be
						implemented, ensure that the hostname is reachable from
						the remote computer.
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="writeConnection" type="string">
						<description>
						Sets the database write connection which is private to
						scmaster. A separate write connection enables different
						permissions on the database level for scmaster and
						clients.
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="strictVersionCheck" type="boolean" default="true">
						<description>
						If enabled, the plugin will check the database schema version and refuse to start
						if the version doesn't match the latest version. If disabled and the an object
						needs to be stored which is incompatible with the database schema this object is
						lost. Leave this option enabled unless you know exactly what are you doing and what
						the consequences are.
						</description>
					</parameter>
				</group>
			</group>
		</configuration>
		<setup>
			<group name="database">
				<input name="enable" type="boolean" default="true">
					<text>Enable database storage</text>
					<description>
						Enables/disables the database. If the database is not enabled the processed
						data is not stored persistently. Leave this option enabled unless you know
						what you are doing.
					</description>
					<option value="false"/>
					<option value="true">
						<input name="backend" type="string" default="mysql">
							<text>Database backend</text>
							<description>
							SeisComP supports different database backends. Select
							the one you want to use. Different backends require
							different additional packages to be installed on your
							host system.
							</description>
							<option value="mysql">
								<description>MySQL server.</description>
								<input name="create" type="boolean" default="true">
									<text>Create database</text>
									<description>
									If you already have a database and want to reuse it, you can skip this step.
									If you want to let setup create the database for you, check this option.
									</description>
									<option value="true">
										<input name="rootpw" type="string" echo="password">
											<text>MYSQL root password</text>
											<description>
											To create the database root access to the database is required. Please
											enter the root password to the database server you are going to use.
											The server hostname will be entered in the next steps.
											</description>
										</input>
										<input name="drop" type="boolean" default="false">
											<text>Drop existing database</text>
											<description>
											When a database with the same name exists already, should it be destroyed
											and recreated? If you say no here, an error will be raised if the database
											to be created already exists.
											</description>
										</input>
									</option>
									<option value="false"/>
								</input>
							</option>
							<option value="postgresql">
								<description>
								Postgresql server. There is currently no support in setup to create the
								database for you. You have to setup the database and user accounts on
								your own. The database schema is installed under share/db/postgresql.sql.
								Note that the database encoding should be UTF8 and that you need
								to set the encoding to 'escape' for PostgreSQL &gt;= 9,
								e.g. &quot;ALTER DATABASE seiscomp3 SET bytea_output TO 'escape';&quot;
								</description>
							</option>
						</input>
						<input name="db" type="string" default="seiscomp3">
							<text>Database name</text>
							<description>
							Database name to use. If you want to avoid conflicts with
							existing databases or if you have multiple installations
							change the default name. If you are unsure, keep the default.
							</description>
						</input>
						<input name="rwhost" type="string" default="localhost">
							<text>Database hostname</text>
							<description>
							The hostname of the computer running the database server.
							In most cases it is this computer (localhost). This hostname is
							private and not published to any client connection to this
							computer.
							</description>
						</input>
						<input name="rwuser" type="string" default="sysop">
							<text>Database read-write user</text>
							<description>
							The database username for read-write access to the database.
							This account will not be visible to clients connecting to your
							system unless read-only and read-write accounts are not separated.
							</description>
						</input>
						<input name="rwpwd" type="string" default="sysop">
							<text>Database read-write password</text>
							<description>
							The database user password for read-write access to the database.
							This account will not be visible to clients connecting to your
							system unless read-only and read-write accounts are not separated.
							</description>
						</input>
						<input name="rohost" type="string" default="localhost">
							<text>Database public hostname</text>
							<description>
							The hostname of the computer running the database server.
							In most cases it is this computer (localhost). This hostname is
							sent to all connected clients who in turn will try to resolve it.
							If all modules run locally you can leave the defaults.
							</description>
						</input>
						<input name="rouser" type="string" default="sysop">
							<text>Database read-only user</text>
							<description>
							The database user that will have read-only access to the database.
							This account will be visible to all clients connecting to your
							system.
							</description>
						</input>
						<input name="ropwd" type="string" default="sysop">
							<text>Database read-only password</text>
							<description>
							The database user password for read-only access to the database.
							This password will be visible to all clients connecting to your
							system.
							</description>
						</input>
					</option>
				</input>
			</group>
		</setup>
	</module>
</seiscomp>
