<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<seiscomp>
	<plugin name="RegionCheck">
		<extends>scevent</extends>
		<description>evrc plugin for scevent</description>
		<configuration>
			<group name="rc">
				<description>
				Test if events lie within or outside a region.
				Events within a region are flagged as positive, outside as negative.
				The event type is set accordingly.
				Add the plugin &quot;evrc&quot; to the  plugins
				parameter to make this feature available.
				</description>
				<parameter name="regions" type="list:string" default="!reject">
					<description>
					The list of closed BNA polygon names defining regions for
					flagging event as positive or negative.
					A polygon name defines a positive region but names with prefix !  (exclamation mark)
					define negative regions. Evaluation is done in the order of the
					polygons. The last matching criteria applies and the event type
					is set accordingly.

					Default: If events are not positive or are negative regions the
					event type is set to &quot;outside of network interest&quot;.
					Default: &quot;!reject&quot;, use &quot;accecpt&quot; to overwrite the default.

					Examples:

					Events are flagged positive within the polygon &quot;germany&quot;:

					germany

					All events are flagged positive but events within the polygon &quot;quarries&quot; are negative:

					accept,!quarries

					Events within the polygon &quot;germany&quot; are flagged positive but
					all other events and events within the polygon &quot;quarries&quot; are negaitve:

					germany,!quarries

					All events are flagged positive but events within the polygon &quot;germany&quot;
					are negative and all events within the polygon &quot;saxony&quot; are positive:

					accept,!germany,saxony
					</description>
				</parameter>
				<parameter name="readEventTypeFromBNA" type="boolean" default="false">
					<description>
						Read the event type from the BNA polygon header. The header must contain
						the type, e.g. header of a polygon with name &quot;quarry&quot;:

						&quot;quarry&quot;,&quot;rank 1&quot;,&quot;eventType: quarry blast&quot;,13

						When active, type superseeds eventTypePositive and eventTypeNegative.
					</description>
				</parameter>
				<parameter name="eventTypePositive" type="string" default="">
					<description>
						New type of an event which is flagged positive. Ignored
						if readEventTypeFromBNA is active.

						Empty: Do not set type
					</description>
				</parameter>
				<parameter name="eventTypeNegative" type="string" default="&quot;outside of network interest&quot;">
					<description>
						New type of an event which is flagged negative. Ignored
						if readEventTypeFromBNA is active.

						Empty means default: &quot;outside of network interest&quot;
					</description>
				</parameter>
			</group>
		</configuration>
	</plugin>
</seiscomp>
