<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<seiscomp>
	<binding module="seedlink" name="minilogger" category="sources">
		<description>SEP064 USB Seismometer Interface</description>
		<configuration>
			<parameter name="port_path_hint" type="string" default="/dev/ttyACM0">
				<description>
				Device path and name of port for USB Seismometer Interface.
				If the specified port cannot be opened or is not a USB Seismometer
				Interface device, all available ports will be scanned.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="allow_set_interface_attribs" type="int" default="1">
				<description>
				Allow low-level setting of port interface attributes when available
				ports are scanned to find a USB Seismometer Interface device, 0=NO, 1=Yes.
				Setting 1 (=Yes) may help successful detection and correct reading of the
				USB Seismometer Interface device, particularly for the RasberryPi, but can
				have adverse effects on other devices, terminals, etc. open on the system.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="mswrite_header_sample_rate" type="double" default="-1">
				<description>
				Sets a fixed sample rate to report in the miniseed file header.
				The default (-1) sets an estimated sample rate based on recent packet start
				times. This estimated sample rate will vary slightly over time, potentially
				producing errors in some software when reading the miniseed files.
				See also: nominal_sample_rate
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="mswrite_data_encoding_type" type="string" default="STEIM2">
				<description>
				SEED data encoding type for writing miniseed files.
				Supported values are: INT16, INT32, STEIM1, STEIM2
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="channel_prefix" type="string" default="SH">
				<description>
				The initial letters to set for the miniseed header 'channel', will be
				prepended to the component.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="component" type="string" default="Z">
				<description>
				Component of seismogram, one of Z, N or E.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="do_settings_sep064" type="int" default="1">
				<description>
				Set sample rate and gain on SEP 064 device, 0=NO, 1=Yes.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="nominal_sample_rate" type="int" default="80">
				<description>
				Nominal sample rate per second, one of 20, 40 or 80.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="nominal_gain" type="int" default="4">
				<description>
				Nominal gain, one of 1, 2 or 4.
				</description>
			</parameter>
		</configuration>
	</binding>
</seiscomp>
