<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<seiscomp>
	<module name="scart" category="Utilities" standalone="true">
		<description>
		Import/export MiniSEED data to/from SDS archives.
		</description>
		<command-line>
			<synopsis>
			scart [options] {archive-dir}
			</synopsis>
			<description>
			The last option has to be the archive directory when dump mode is enabled.
			When no archive directory is explicitly given,
			$SEISCOMP_ROOT/acquisition/archive or the current directory
			is used depending on whether $SEISCOMP_ROOT has been set or not.
			The default operation mode is import. That means that a multiplexed
			MiniSEED file or another record source such as ArcLink is used to import
			records into a SDS structure.
			</description>
			<group name="">
				<option flag="I">
					<description>
					Specify the recordstream URL when in import mode.
					When using another recordstream than a file (like ArcLink) a stream
					list file is required (default is file://- (stdin))
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="t" argument="timewindow">
					<description>
					Specify the time window (as one properly quoted string) to dump
					records for. Times are UTC and separated by a tilde &quot;~&quot;.
					To dump one hour of waveform data between 2008/01/01 00:00:00 and
					2008/01/01 01:00:00 use
					&lt;-t &quot;2008-01-01 00:00:00~2008-01-01 01:00:00&quot;&gt;.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="d" long-flag="dump">
					<description>
					Set export (dump) mode. Records are fetched from an archive and
					stored in a file (or pipe).
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="l" long-flag="list" argument="file">
					<description>
					Uses a stream list file instead of defined networks and channels
					(-n and -c are ignored). Line format: starttime;endtime;streamID.
					The time format is the same as described in option '-t'.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="s" long-flag="sort">
					<description>
					Sort records by [start-]time. To sort records by their endtime use -E.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="E">
					<description>
					Sort records according to their end time (default is start time).
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="m" long-flag="modify">
					<description>
					Modify the record time for real time playback when in export mode.
					The first record time is NOW. The relative time of successive records
					to the first one are kept.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option long-flag="speed">
					<description>
					Specify the speed to dump the records. A value of 0 means no delay
					otherwise speed is a multiplier of the real time difference between
					the records. When feeding the records directly into the replay pipe
					a value of 1 (real time) is recommended.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="n" argument="networks">
					<description>
					Network list of networks to dump (comma separated) (default is *).
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="c" argument="channels">
					<description>
					Specify the channel filter for the dumped streams as regular
					expression (default is (B|S|M|H)(L|H)(Z|N|E)). To dump only the
					BHZ, BHN and BHE streams use BH(Z|N|E).
					</description>
				</option>
				<option long-flag="files" argument="count">
					<description>
					Specify the number of file handles to cache (default is 100).
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="v" long-flag="verbose">
					<description>
					Verbose mode.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option long-flag="test">
					<description>
					Test mode, no record output. This switch is useful for debugging.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="h" long-flag="help">
					<description>
					Display a help message.
					</description>
				</option>
			</group>
		</command-line>
	</module>
</seiscomp>
