<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<seiscomp>
	<module name="slarchive" category="Acquisition" standalone="true">
		<description>SeedLink client for data stream archiving</description>
		<configuration>
			<parameter name="address" type="string" default="127.0.0.1">
				<description>
				Host of the Seedlink server to connect to. If the acquisition
				is running on one system nothing needs to be changed.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="port" type="int" default="18000">
				<description>
				The port of the Seedlink server to connect to. If the acquisition
				is running on one system this port must match the configured
				local Seedlink port.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="archive" type="string" default="var/lib/archive">
				<description>
				Path to waveform archive where all data is stored. Relative paths
				(as the default) are treated relative to the installation
				directory ($SEISCOMP_ROOT).
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="buffer" type="int" default="1000">
				<description>
				Number of records (512 byte units) to buffer before flushing to
				disk.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="delay" type="int" default="30">
				<description>
				The network reconnect delay (in seconds) for the connection
				to the SeedLink server. If the connection breaks for any
				reason this will govern how soon a reconnection should be
				attempted. The default value is 30 seconds.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="networkTimeout" type="int" default="900">
				<description>
				The network timeout (in seconds) for the connection to the
				SeedLink server. If no data [or keep alive packets?] are received
				in this time range the connection is closed and re-established
				(after the reconnect delay has expired). The default value is
				600 seconds. A value of 0 disables the timeout.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="idleTimeout" type="int" default="300">
				<description>
				Timeout for closing idle data stream files in seconds. The idle
				time of the data streams is only checked when some packets has
				arrived. If no packets arrived no idle stream files will be
				closed. There is no reason to change this parameter except for
				the unusual cases where the process is running against an open
				file number limit. Default is 300 seconds.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="keepalive" type="int" default="0">
				<description>
				Interval (in seconds) at which keepalive (heartbeat) packets
				are sent to the server. Keepalive packets are only sent if
				nothing is received within the interval. This requires a
				Seedlink version >= 3.
				</description>
			</parameter>
		</configuration>
		<command-line>
			<synopsis>
				slarchive [OPTION]... [host][:][port]
			</synopsis>
			<description>
				Address ([host][:][port]) is a required argument. It specifies the address
				of the SeedLink server in host:port format. Either the host, port or both
				can be omitted. If host is omitted then localhost is assumed,
				i.e. ':18000' implies 'localhost:18000'. If the port is omitted
				then 18000 is assumed, i.e. 'localhost' implies 'localhost:18000'.
				If only ':' is specified 'localhost:18000' is assumed.
			</description>
			<group name="">
				<option flag="V">
					<description>Print program version and exit.</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="h">
					<description>Print program usage and exit.</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="v">
					<description>
						Be more verbose. This flag can be used multiple times (&quot;-v -v&quot; or &quot;-vv&quot;)
						for more verbosity. One flag: report basic handshaking (link configuration) details and
						briefly report each packet received. Two flags: report the details of the handshaking,
						each packet received and detailed connection diagnostics.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="p">
					<description>
						Print details of received Mini-SEED data records. This flag can be used multiple times
						(&quot;-p -p&quot; or &quot;-pp&quot;) for more detail. One flag: a single summary line
						for each data packet received. Two flags: details of the Mini-SEED data records received,
						including information from fixed header and 100/1000/1001 blockettes.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="nd" argument="delay">
					<description>
						The network reconnect delay (in seconds) for the connection to the SeedLink server.
						If the connection breaks for any reason this will govern how soon a reconnection should
						be attempted. The default value is 30 seconds.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="nt" argument="timeout">
					<description>
						The network timeout (in seconds) for the connection to the SeedLink server. If no data
						[or keep alive packets?] are received in this time range the connection is closed and
						re-established (after the reconnect delay has expired). The default value is 600 seconds.
						A value of 0 disables the timeout.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="k" argument="keepalive">
					<description>
						Interval (in seconds) at which keepalive (heartbeat) packets are sent to the server.
						Keepalive packets are only sent if nothing is received within the interval. Requires SeedLink
						version &gt;= 3.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="x" argument="statefile[:interval]">
					<description>
						During client shutdown the last received sequence numbers and time stamps (start times)
						for each data stream will be saved in this file. If this file exists upon startup the information
						will be used to resume the data streams from the point at which they were stopped. In this way the
						client can be stopped and started without data loss, assuming the data are still available on the
						server. If an interval is specified the state will be saved every interval in that packets are
						received. Otherwise the state will be saved only on normal program termination.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="i" argument="timeout">
					<description>
						Timeout for closing idle data stream files in seconds. The idle time of the data streams is
						only checked when some packets has arrived. If no packets arrived no idle stream files will be
						closed. There is no reason to change this parameter except for the unusual cases where the
						process is running against an open file number limit. Default is 300 seconds.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="d">
					<description>
						Configure the connection in "dial-up" mode. The remote server will close the connection when
						it has sent all of the data in its buffers for the selected data streams. This is opposed to
						the normal behavior of waiting indefinitely for data.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="b">
					<description>Configure the connection in &quot;batch&quot; mode.</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="Fi[:overlap]">
					<description>
						Future check initially. Check the last Mini-SEED data record in an existing archive file
						and do not write new data to that file if it is older than a certain overlap. The default
						overlap limit is 2 seconds; the overlap can be specified by appending a colon and the desired
						overlap limit in seconds to the option. If the overlap is exceeded an error message will be
						logged once for each time the file is opened. This option makes sense only for archive formats
						where each unique data stream is written to a unique file (e.g. SDS format). If a data stream
						is closed due to timeout (see option -i) the initial future check will be preformed when the
						file is re-opened.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="Fc[:overlap]">
					<description>
						Future check continuously. Available only for archive Mini-SEED data records. Check if the
						first sample of the record is older than the last sample of the previous record for a given
						archive file, within a certain overlap. The default overlap limit is 2 seconds; the overlap
						can be specified by appending a colon and the desired overlap limit in seconds to the option.
						If the overlap is exceeded an error message will be logged once until either a non-overlapping
						packet is received or a new archive file is used. This option only makes sense for archive
						formats where each unique data stream is written to a unique file (e.g. SDS format).
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="A" argument="format">
					<description>
						If specified, all received packets (Mini-SEED records) will be appended to a directory/file
						structure defined by format. All directories implied in the format string will be created if
						necessary. The option may be used multiple times to write received packets to multiple archives.
						See the section &quot;archiving data&quot;.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="SDS" argument="path">
					<description>
						If specified, all received packets (Mini-SEED records) will be saved into a Simple Data
						Structure (SDS) dir/file structure starting at the specified directory. This directory and
						all subdirectories will be created if necessary. This option is a preset of the '-A' option.
						The SDS dir/file structure is:

						&lt;SDSdir&gt;/&lt;YEAR&gt;/&lt;NET&gt;/&lt;STA&gt;/&lt;CHAN.TYPE&gt;/NET.STA.LOC.CHAN.TYPE.YEAR.DAY

						Details are mentioned later on.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="BUD" argument="path">
					<description>
						If specified, all received waveform data packets (Mini-SEED data records) will be saved into
						a Buffer of Uniform Data (BUD) dir/file structure starting at the specified directory.
						This directory and all subdirectories will be created if necessary. This option is a preset
						of the '-A' option. The BUD dir/file structure is:

						&lt;BUDdir&gt;/&lt;NET&gt;/&lt;STA&gt;/STA.NET.LOC.CHAN.YEAR.DAY
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="DLOG" argument="DLOGdir">
					<description>
						If specified, all received packets (Mini-SEED data records) will be saved into an old style
						SeisComP/datalog dir/file structure starting at the specified directory. This directory and
						all subdirectories will be created if necessary. This option is a preset of the '-A' option.
						The DLOG dir/file structure is:

						&lt;DLOGdir&gt;/&lt;STA&gt;/[LOC.]&lt;CHAN&gt;.&lt;TYPE&gt;/STA.NET.CHAN.TYPE.YEAR.DAY.HHMM
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="l" argument="streamfile">
					<description>
						The given file contains a list of streams. This option implies multi-station mode.
						The format of the stream list file is given below in the section &quot;stream list file&quot;.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="s" argument="selectors">
					<description>
						Defining default selectors. If no multi-station data streams are configured these selectors
						will be used for uni-station mode. Otherwise these selectors will be used when no selectors
						are specified for a given stream with the '-S' or '-l' options.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="S" argument="stream[:selectors]">
					<description>
						The connection will be configured in multi-station mode with optional SeedLink selectors
						for each station, see examples below. Stream should be provided in NET_STA format. If no
						selectors are provided for a given stream, the default selectors will be used, if defined.

						Requires SeedLink &gt;= 2.5.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="tw" argument="start:[end]">
					<description>
						Specifying a time window for the data streams that is applied by the server. The format
						for both times is year,month,day,hour,min,sec; for example: "2002,08,05,14,00:2002,08,05,14,15,00".
						The end time is optional but the colon must be present. If no end time is specified the
						server will send data indefinitely. This option will override any saved state information.

						Warning: time windowing might be disabled on the remote server.

						Requires SeedLink &gt;= 3.
					</description>
				</option>
			</group>
		</command-line>
	</module>

	<binding module="slarchive">
		<description>
		Configures what streams of a station should be archived and for
		how long.
		</description>
		<configuration>
			<parameter name="selectors" type="list:string">
				<description>
				List of stream selectors. If left empty all available
				streams will be requested. See slarchive manpage for
				more information.
				</description>
			</parameter>
			<parameter name="keep" type="int" default="30">
				<description>
				Number of days the data is kept in the archive. This
				requires purge_datafile to be run as cronjob.
				</description>
			</parameter>
		</configuration>
	</binding>
</seiscomp>
